# **Muzaffar Munir**

muzafarmunir@gmail.com

(+92) 340-6168990

Lahore, Pakistan

LinkedIn

**Profile** 

### **Summary**

With **5years** of experience as a Full Stack Engineer, I've sharpened my skills in utilizing **JavaScript** frameworks to build adaptable web applications that meet the diverse needs of communities. Throughout my professional journey, I've actively participated in every application development life cycle phase, starting from the initial concept and extending to customization based on customer requirements. Ensuring seamless communication within the development team has always been my priority. In my past experiences, I have contributed applications from different industries, including Retail, Real Estate, and Health Tech.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Tkxel - Senior Software Engineer

April 2023 - Current Reston, VA

- Following Agile and Scrum to meet standards and having Daily standups with the team
- Client communication to discuss the requirements.
- Identify issues and provide fixes along with developing new features
- Working on AWS serverless resources such as Lambda functions, DynamoDB, EC2, Cloud Formation, S3 Appsync, CodePipeline and CognitoUser
- Working on GraphQL to write APIs for data communications
- Manage a team of 4 resources to deliver application as required

#### Virtual Force - Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2021 - Apr 2023 Lahore, PK

- Build strategy for application stack upgrade
- Stack upgrade from AngularJS to Angular(v12)
- Stack upgrade to Latest **NodeJs** and MongoDb version
- Upgrade video consultation using twilio and other libraries was a big challenge
- Frequently review logs to make sure things working smoothly in production as expected
- Code reviews and bootcamps for new resources
- Career counseling and training for junior resources

#### **OptimaGeeks** – Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2018 - Nov 2021

Lahore, PK

- Core understanding of Restful services and Single page applications
- Restful Api development using NodeJs(expressJs) and PHP
- Identify and solve backend related issues using NodeJs and PHP
- Api integration in AngularJs Application and manual testing
- Stack upgrade from AngularJs to Angular
- Stack Upgrade from PHP to NodeJS(expressJS)
- Gain extensive knowledge on MongoDB

- Work on Laravel and VueJs application
- Migrated Applications from DigitalOcean to AWS

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Gujrat - B.S. Information Technology

August 2014 - July 2018

Gujrat, PK

## **SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, Angular, NodeJS, NestJs, ExpressJS

AWS: S3, Lambda Functions, S3, EC2, DynamoDB, Cloudformation

Databases: SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL), NoSQL, DynamoDB

Version Controls: Github, Gitlab, BitBucket, SVN

Tools: Jira, Trello